{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Molar absorbtivities of compounds exhibiting charge transfer absorption are", "opta": "small", "optb": "moderate", "optc": "large", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Molar absorbtivity is the measure of the", "opta": "amount of light absorbed per unit length", "optb": "amount of light absorbed per unit concentration", "optc": "amount of light reflected and absorbed per unit concentration", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following relationships between absorbance and %transmittance is incorrect?", "opta": "A = log10 100 / %T", "optb": "A = 2 - log10 %T", "optc": "A = log10 1 / T", "optd": "All are correct", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why is it generally preferable to use absorbance as a measure of absorption rather than % transmittance?", "opta": "Because %T cannot be measured as accurately as absorbance", "optb": "Because %T is dependant on the power of the incident radiation", "optc": "Because absorbance is proportional to the concentration of the analyte, whereas %T is not", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the past, IR spectra had to be aquired one wavelength at a time, which took a long time. Today quick spectra is due to the", "opta": "the Fourier Transfer Algorithm allows us to scan all frequencies at once", "optb": "light is faster today that it used to be", "optc": "absence of broad spectrum of wavelenth", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not an IR vibrational mode?", "opta": "Stretching", "optb": "Scissoring", "optc": "Rocking", "optd": "Rolling", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following will oscillate the fastest?", "opta": "A large mass on a weak spring", "optb": "A large mass on a stiff spring", "optc": "A small mass on a stiff spring", "optd": "A small mass on a weak spring", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the equation, A = \u03b5 bc, what quantity is represented by \"\u03b5\"?", "opta": "Absorbtivity", "optb": "Molar absorbtivity", "optc": "Path length", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why must the voltage supplied to a tungsten lamp be very stable?", "opta": "Because if it wasn't, the lamp would bum out", "optb": "Because amount of energy the lamp emits is proportional to the fourth power of the operating voltage", "optc": "Because the lamp will only function at a specific voltage", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Where does a carbonyl (C=0) stretch appear in an IR spectrum?", "opta": "1740-1720", "optb": "1870-1650", "optc": "3640-3250", "optd": "160-110", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following components of a monochromator is the dispersing element?", "opta": "The collimating lens", "optb": "The entrance slit", "optc": "The diffraction grating", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A simple harmonic oscillator may absorb energy", "opta": "at anytime.", "optb": "when the frequencies match exactly", "optc": "when the amplitudes are the same.", "optd": "at no time.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "UV-Vis spectroscopy of organic compounds is usually concerned with which electronic transition(s)?", "opta": "\u03c3 \u2192 \u03c3*", "optb": "n \u2192 \u03c3*", "optc": "n \u2192 \u03c0* and \u03c0 \u2192 \u03c0*", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Vibrational spectroscopy is", "opta": "a large mass on a weak spring", "optb": "a flashlight through a prism and shake it", "optc": "a class of spectroscopic techniques which analyzes molecular motions", "optd": "an Infrared spectroscopy", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why are rotational transitions of little use to a spectroscopist?", "opta": "Because the energy required to induce a rotational transition is so small that it cannot be measured", "optb": "Because rotational transitions are extremely rare", "optc": "Because, in liquids and solids, spectral lines corresponding to rotational transitions are broadened as the result of molecular collisions and other interactions", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Beer's Law states that", "opta": "absorbance is proportional to both the path length and concentration of the absorbing species", "optb": "absorbance is proportional to the log of the concentration of the absorbing species", "optc": "absorbance is equal to P0 / P", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}